=Spring Fever= =Episode 5=
=حمى الربيع= =الحلقة 5=
(Father, where are you going? Don't abandon me!)
(أبي إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟ لا تتركني!)
(Father, don't leave! Father!)
(أبي لا تذهب! يا أبي!)
(Princess He'an died giving birth to the Young Lord.)
(توفيت الأميرة هيآن أثناء ولادة اللورد الشاب.)
(His birth caused her death.)
(ولادته سبب موتها.)
(I'm setting off on my cultivation path. Take good care of the Young Lord.)
(أنا أبدأ في مسار زراعتي. اعتني جيدًا بالسيد الشاب.)
(Mother,)
(الأم،)
(all my life, I believed)
(طوال حياتي كنت أؤمن)
(you died while giving birth to me.)
(لقد مت أثناء ولادتك لي.)
(But that accusation letter claims)
(لكن رسالة الإتهام تدعي)
(your death wasn't an accident.)
(موتك لم يكن حادثًا.)
(This time, I've come)
(هذه المرة، لقد أتيت)
(to uncover the truth.)
(لكشف الحقيقة.)
Shi'an,
شيآن،
your mother's life remains at stake.
لا تزال حياة والدتك على المحك.
Aren't you concerned?
ألا تشعر بالقلق؟
Jin is truly unharmed.
جين لم يصب بأذى حقًا.
Take this potion.
خذ هذه الجرعة.
I'll take you to her.
سوف آخذك إليها.
Potion?
جرعة؟
What kind of potion?
أي نوع من الجرعة؟
It's the sterility potion.
إنها جرعة العقم.
Your failed lamp offering,
عرض مصباحك الفاشل،
angering the deities and causing Jinzhi's miscarriage.
مما أثار غضب الآلهة وتسبب في إجهاض جينزي.
She may never conceive again.
ربما لا تتمكن من الحمل مرة أخرى.
This cannot escape family rules. I couldn't ignore it.
هذا لا يُمكن أن يُفلت من قواعد العائلة. لم أستطع تجاهله.
Lord Shen already proved my innocence that day.
لقد أثبت اللورد شين براءتي في ذلك اليوم.
And I offered her a way to save face.
وعرضت عليها طريقة لإنقاذ ماء وجهها.
Yet in the end,
ولكن في النهاية،
the one who doubts me
الشخص الذي يشك بي
turns out to be you.
اتضح أنك أنت.
I do believe you, but...
أنا أصدقك، ولكن...
What?
ماذا؟
Mother.
الأم.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Let me go!
دعني أذهب!
Shi'an.
شيعان.
A'man.
أمان.
Let me go!
دعني أذهب!
Be gentle with her!
كن لطيفا معها!
What?
ماذا؟
Hurry, Shi'an!
عجل يا شيآن!
Let me go!
دعني أذهب!
Do it now!
افعلها الآن!
Shi'an.
شيعان.
My life remains in her hands.
حياتي لا تزال بين يديها.
A'man.
أمان.
Shi'an.
شيعان.
We already have Jin.
لدينا جين بالفعل.
Even if you never conceive,
حتى لو لم تتصوري أبدا،
I'll protect you both.
سأحميكما معًا.
(I'm sorry.)
(أنا آسف.)
(Beat me or curse me after taking it. I'll accept it all.)
(اضربني أو شتمني بعد أخذه. سأقبل كل شيء.)
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
A'man.
أمان.
Jinzhi promised
وعد جينتشي
that as long as you never conceive,
طالما أنك لم تنجبي أبدًا،
she'll stop tormenting you.
ستتوقف عن تعذيبك.
Is this what you meant
هل هذا ما قصدته
by treating me well?
من خلال معاملتي بشكل جيد؟
I had no choice.
لم يكن لدي خيار.
You always have choices.
لديك دائما خيارات.
You just never choose me.
أنت لم تختارني أبدًا.
It's just that
إنه فقط ذلك
when trouble comes,
عندما تأتي المشاكل،
you always discard me.
أنت تتجاهلني دائمًا.
That's not true.
هذا ليس صحيحا.
A'man.
أمان.
A'man, what's wrong?
أمان، ما الأمر؟
A'man, what's happening?
أمان، ماذا يحدث؟
A'man.
أمان.
W-What's happening?
و- ماذا يحدث؟
A'man, what's wrong?
أمان، ما الأمر؟
A'man.
أمان.
A'man!
أمان!
Get the physician!
احصل على الطبيب!
Hurry, get the physician!
اسرعوا واحضروا الطبيب!
Wait. Wasn't it a sterility potion?
انتظر. أليست جرعة عقم؟
A'man.
أمان.
She's been poisoned.
لقد تم تسميمها.
She's dead.
لقد ماتت.
Bury her.
ادفنها.
You lied.
لقد كذبت.
You lied!
لقد كذبت!
Why?
لماذا؟
Why did you kill her?
لماذا قتلتها؟
I killed her?
أنا قتلتها؟
What have I done?
ماذا فعلت؟
Wasn't it you who fed her the potion?
ألم تكن أنت الذي أطعمها الجرعة؟
You...
أنت...
I'll get the physician.
سأحضر الطبيب.
Mother, watch over her.
أمي، اهتمي بها.
It's too late.
لقد فات الأوان.
And if this gets out,
وإذا خرج هذا،
you will be the murderer, not me.
أنت ستكون القاتل، وليس أنا.
Now that I'm satisfied.
الآن أنا راضية.
Your mother will remain unharmed.
ستبقى والدتك سالمة.
The funds your mother embezzled...
الأموال التي اختلستها والدتك...
I've reimbursed them with my dowry.
لقد سددت لهم مهري.
Shi'an,
شيآن،
Concubine Ye has...
المحظية يي لديها ...
She's already... Just bury her, okay?
إنها بالفعل... فقط ادفنها، حسنًا؟
Shi'an.
شيعان.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Don't you keep having the same nightmare?
ألا تستمر في الحصول على نفس الكابوس؟
I tell the nightmare to this brocade box.
أخبر الكابوس لصندوق الديباج هذا.
Lock it inside and bury it.
أغلقه بالداخل وادفنه.
Then you'll never have the same nightmare again.
وبعدها لن تعاني من نفس الكابوس مرة أخرى.
Really?
حقًا؟
Yes.
نعم.
My grandmother taught me that. It works.
علمتني جدتي ذلك. إنه يعمل.
Well...
حسنًا...
I'll trust you for now.
سأثق بك الآن.
A'man,
أمان،
whenever you're sad
كلما كنت حزينا
scared,
مقدس،
or in danger, just tell me.
أو في خطر، فقط أخبرني.
I'll protect you.
سأحميك.
Always.
دائماً.
♪Wine like steel, steel with wine♪
♪النبيذ كالفولاذ، والفولاذ مع النبيذ♪
Okay.
تمام.
Shi'an.
شيعان.
I'll bury it then.
سأدفنه إذن.
Bury it.
ادفنها.
Bury it all.
دفن كل ذلك.
Mother.
الأم.
Wake up.
استيقظ.
Wake up, please.
استيقظ من فضلك.
Jin.
إحساس.
A penal slave begets a criminal slave.
العبد الجزائي ينجب عبدا مجرمًا.
Take them and sell them off.
خذهم وبيعهم.
Mother.
الأم.
Jin.
إحساس.
She's not a criminal slave.
إنها ليست عبدة مجرمة.
She's not my daughter.
إنها ليست ابنتي.
Mother.
الأم.
She's not a criminal slave.
إنها ليست عبدة مجرمة.
Let her go!
اسمح لها أن تذهب!
Jin.
إحساس.
Mother.
الأم.
(How am I still alive?)
(كيف لا أزال على قيد الحياة؟)
(Where am I?)
(أين أنا؟)
I can't die.
لا أستطيع أن أموت.
(I can't die.)
(لا أستطيع أن أموت.)
(Can't die...)
(لا أستطيع أن أموت...)
What?
ماذا؟
Reluctant to come out?
متردد في الخروج؟
How do you know I am here?
كيف عرفت أني هنا؟
You're a crucial lead in my investigation.
أنت دليل حاسم في تحقيقاتي.
I know
أنا أعرف
your every move.
كل تحركاتك.
Jin isn't with Xia Jinzhi.
جين ليس مع Xia Jinzhi.
The potion Lu Shi'an gave me was poisoned.
الجرعة التي أعطاني إياها لو شيآن كانت مسمومة.
You knew all this.
لقد عرفت كل هذا.
Did you come to mock me?
هل أتيت لتسخر مني؟
I told you before.
لقد قلت لك من قبل.
You
أنت
won't yield until you hit the end.
لن تستسلم حتى تصل إلى النهاية.
Under the guise of drug primer,
تحت ستار دواء تمهيدي،
Xia Jinzhi's maid
خادمة Xia Jinzhi
purchased arsenic from several pharmacies.
اشتريت الزرنيخ من عدة صيدليات.
The potion Lu Shi'an gave you
الجرعة التي أعطاك إياها لو شيآن
was originally poisoned.
لقد تم تسميمه في الأصل.
I swapped it.
لقد قمت بتبديله.
I'm your savior.
انا منقذك.
Is this how you treat me?
هل هكذا تعاملني؟
Watching me drown in misery,
يراني أغرق في البؤس،
while you stand by idly.
بينما أنت تقف مكتوف الأيدي.
If you enjoy spectacles so much,
إذا كنت تستمتع بالمشاهدة كثيرًا،
why bother saving me at all?
لماذا تهتم بإنقاذي على الإطلاق؟
You're heartless.
أنت بلا قلب.
You're meddlesome.
أنت فضولي.
Self-righteous!
متعجرف!
Opportunistic!
انتهازي!
Cruel!
فظ!
Despicable!
حقير!
Stupid.
غبي.
Stupid?
غبي؟
Yes.
نعم.
I'm stupid.
انا غبي.
Stupid enough to be sheltered by the Lu family all these years
غبي بما يكفي ليحظى بالحماية من عائلة لو كل هذه السنوات
and meekly endured everything.
وتحملت كل شيء بهدوء.
Stupid enough to believe that even though Lu Shi'an
غبي بما يكفي ليصدق أنه على الرغم من أن لو شيآن
didn't register me under civilian registration,
لم يسجلوني في السجل المدني،
he'd take good care of Jin.
سوف يعتني بجين جيدًا.
Stupid enough to follow him knowingly
غبي بما يكفي لمتابعته عن علم
into this trap,
في هذا الفخ،
trying to prove he hadn't deceived me.
يحاول أن يثبت لي أنه لم يخدعني.
Stupid enough to believe sincerity begets sincerity.
غبي بما فيه الكفاية ليصدق أن الإخلاص يولد الإخلاص.
Yet in this world, sincerity is the cheapest commodity.
ولكن في هذا العالم، الصدق هو أرخص السلع.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Just now,
الآن،
I shouldn't have
لا ينبغي لي أن أفعل ذلك
spoken to you that way.
لقد تكلمت إليك بهذه الطريقة.
You were right.
لقد كنت على حق.
I was deluded.
لقد كنت مخدوعًا.
Being scolded into awareness is better.
إن توبيخك حتى تدرك ذلك أفضل.
Some people
بعض الناس
never wake up
لا تستيقظ أبدًا
before they die.
قبل أن يموتوا.
Come on.
تعال.
To survival.
من أجل البقاء.
Gao Fu.
جاو فو.
My lord.
سيدي.
The fire seems not strong enough.
يبدو أن النار ليست قوية بما فيه الكفاية.
Fetch more firewood.
احضر المزيد من الحطب.
This fire's strong. Enough firewood.
هذه النار قوية. هناك ما يكفي من الحطب.
There is plenty.
هناك الكثير.
Not enough.
ليس كافيا.
Alright then.
حسنا إذن.
Lord Shen,
اللورد شين،
I accept the partnership
أقبل الشراكة
you proposed earlier.
لقد اقترحت في وقت سابق.
Let's make a deal.
دعونا نعقد صفقة.
I'll protect you and your daughter from mistreatment in the Lu family.
سأحميك وابنتك من سوء المعاملة في عائلة لو.
And you tell me
وأنت تخبرني
everything you know about the Lu family
كل ما تعرفه عن عائلة لو
and Ningzhou Prefecture.
ومحافظة نينغتشو.
How do I know your intentions?
كيف أعرف نواياك؟
Why should I trust you?
لماذا يجب أن أثق بك؟
They treated you so poorly.
لقد عاملوك بشكل سيء للغاية.
Yet you still care about their interests?
ولكنك لا تزال مهتما بمصالحهم؟
You can't truly love that spineless man, right?
لا يمكنك حقًا أن تحب هذا الرجل الضعيف، أليس كذلك؟
Listen.
يستمع.
The Lu family took me in, for better or worse.
لقد أخذتني عائلة لو، للأفضل أو الأسوأ.
Shi'an might be weak, but he's my daughter's father.
قد يكون شيآن ضعيفًا، لكنه والد ابنتي.
You're just an outsider.
أنت مجرد شخص غريب.
Why should I trust you?
لماذا يجب أن أثق بك؟
Xia Jinzhi will never conceive again.
شيا جينتشي لن تتمكن من الحمل مرة أخرى.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
Nothing specific.
لا شيء محدد.
Just testing if any affection remains
مجرد اختبار إذا كان هناك أي عاطفة متبقية
between you and Lu Shi'an.
بينك وبين لو شيآن.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
Some remains.
بعض البقايا.
But not much.
ولكن ليس كثيرا.
Fine. When you regret this,
حسناً. عندما تندم على هذا،
come find me.
تعال لتجدني.
Okay.
تمام.
So,
لذا،
what are you going to do next?
ماذا ستفعل بعد ذلك؟
Return to the Lu family.
العودة إلى عائلة لو.
♪Grind flesh between grit and stone♪
♪طحن اللحم بين الحصى والحجر♪
♪Sink into pain, only then are pearls born♪
♪الغرق في الألم، حينها فقط تولد اللآلئ♪
♪Wait until abyssal darkness stains every inch of skin♪
♪انتظر حتى يلطخ الظلام السحيق كل شبر من الجلد♪
♪Then comes the time to chase the dawn♪
♪ثم يأتي الوقت لمطاردة الفجر♪
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
♪سأمسح الرمال المتربة♪
♪Passing wind♪
♪ريح عابرة♪
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
♪تشابك شعري في الرقص♪
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
♪سأستند إلى حضنه♪
♪Wade through deep seas♪
♪خوض البحار العميقة♪
♪Bathing in affection♪
♪الاستحمام في المودة♪
♪Condensing into rain♪
♪تكثف إلى مطر♪
♪Who cast a frantic, lingering glance♪
♪الذي ألقى نظرة محمومة ومتباطئة♪
♪Carrying endless tenderness♪
♪تحمل حنانًا لا نهاية له♪
♪Gazing through eons of moonlit winds♪
♪التحديق عبر عصور من الرياح المضاءة بالقمر♪
♪Turn tears to pearls and cradle them within♪
♪حوّل الدموع إلى لآلئ واحتضنها في داخلك♪
♪Henceforth we walk the mortal realm♪
♪من الآن فصاعدا نسير في عالم البشر♪
♪Across vast mountains and rivers♪
♪عبر الجبال والأنهار الشاسعة♪
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
♪سأمسح الرمال المتربة♪
♪Passing wind♪
♪ريح عابرة♪
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
♪تشابك شعري في الرقص♪
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
♪سأستند إلى حضنه♪
♪Wade through deep seas♪
♪خوض البحار العميقة♪
♪Bathing in affection♪
♪الاستحمام في المودة♪
♪Condensing into rain♪
♪تكثف إلى مطر♪